Downloaded @ subs4free.club
Elwood.
Elwood?
El.
Mama, you see El?
He's out back,
looking like he fell out.
Damn, Evelyn.
You just gonna lay 'em all out?
Gin is gin.
Y'all know Percy can't count
and drink at the same time.
You too tired, Percy?
After this next loss,
I'm gonna have to hear
your mouth all the way to Cali.
No, look, she
knows she ain't driving.
She complaining already.
You know what I'm
sayin'? She... Look.
She knows she ain't driving,
she complaining already.
What you need to do is
put that boy to bed.
No, what you need
to do is mind your business
and get what's coming to you.
What's coming to me?
All right,
Elwood. Get on down now.
Knock knock.
I'm gonna get
what's coming to me.
I'll clean it, Mama.
Come back and
help me win, Evelyn.
You hear?
I said I'd do
the washing up, Mama.
At least let
the child know you're leaving.
Mmm-hmm.
Ow.
Ow!
Hey, Elwood.
Oh, I'm making me a
Elwood bed sandwich.
Oh, Elwood.
Elwood.
Baby, I'm not going anywhere.
I'm not going anywhere.
Come here. Come on.
Nana's not going nowhere.
Come here.
Hattie,
don't you look mod.
Nobody gonna call her grandma.
I'd be glad
to have a grandson
that would carry my shopping.
You raised a
fine young boy, Hattie.
Well, Elwood
didn't need much rightin'.
He spends more time
reading than anything else.
Uh-huh.
You hear about
all the goings-on in Selma?
Mmm-hmm.
Mr. Parker
telling us not to talk
about political
things on the clock.
Said, "That don't got
nothing to do with you all."
Hell it don't.
Long as we working,
I don't see how it
makes a difference.
And we work hard, too.
Well, Jim Crow just ain't gonna
slink off his wicked self.
...however difficult
the moment...
Yes, sir.
...however
frustrating the hour,
- it will not be long.
- No, sir.
Because truth crushed to earth
- will rise again.
- Yes, sir.
- How long? Not long.
Because no lie can live forever.
Yes, sir.
- How long? Not long.
- How long?
Because you shall
reap what you sow.
Yes, sir.
- How long? Not long.
- How long?
The first order of business
in my class will be
to strike out all the latest
epithets of white youths,
which are quite imaginative.
Mr. Hill,
you a Freedom Rider?
That's how you got that
scar over your eye?
Nashville.
White man slugged
me with a tire iron.
Hello.
Where'd you come from?
Two of
the 850-pound satellites
have orbited the Moon,
photographing and
mapping wide areas,
sometimes sweeping as low as
25 miles above the surface.
Here are some of the pictures.
Pictures helping to determine
the height and slope
of lunar mountains,
and the depth of craters.
These remarkable views
show the crater Copernicus.
Pictures too of the
back side of the Moon.
And a view of Earth from
240,000 miles in space.
- Mr. Marconi?
- Yes.
Very nice to
finally meet you, sir.
- Oh, thank you.
- I've heard a lot about you.
Oh, well.
I'm, uh... I'm
looking for Elwood.
- I'm his teacher.
- Oh. Uh...
Right there.
- Mr. Hill.
- Mr. Elwood.
Don't worry. Good news.
You know that colored college
just south of Tallahassee?
Melvin Griggs Technical School?
They've just opened up courses
to high-achieving
high-school students.
And I thought of you
right off the bat.
Well, that
sounds great, Mr. Hill.
But I... I don't think
we have the money
to pay for classes like that.
Oh. Well, that's the thing.
They're free.
They are?
This fall, at least.
So word gets out
in the community.
Imagine a textbook with
nothing to cross out.
Here you go, sir.
We pass on the expressway
going to the airport in Atlanta,
we pass by what is
known as Funtown.
I didn't wanna...
...have to tell
my little daughter
that she couldn't go to Funtown
because of the
color of her skin.
To make us feel
that we do not count.
We must believe in our
souls that we are somebody,
that we are significant...
...that we are worthful,
and we must walk the
streets of life every day
with this sense of dignity
and this sense of somebody-ness.
For the
ninth consecutive day,
those students
continued their protests
against segregation and...
You can't pull us apart.
Yeah.
Mr. Hill
said you might come.
We're organizing bail. Can
we count on you, Elwood?
Yes.
I can give half my paycheck.
I'll be back next week.
Glad you felt the
need to stand up.
Well, it was a good
photograph of him at least.
Now, ain't you proud
of your Elwood for steppin' up.
Of course I'm
proud he was there.
His mama would be
proud of him, too.
Yeah,
she came back now, she
wouldn't recognize her boy.
That theater was showing
The Ugly American
and Invaders from Mars.
Has everyone in Leon
County gone crazy?
All right, yeah, I'll tell him.
- Bye, now.
- All right. Bye.
Nana, next time,
I wanna do the civil
disobedience part.
I love you, El.
I love you too, Nana.
- You hungry?
- No, I'm okay.
- ♪ Walk through With the
valley ♪ - ♪ God knows I know ♪
♪ Every child of God
Has the assurance ♪
♪ There'll be peace
Through the valley ♪
♪ David said, "Though I
walk Through the valley ♪
♪ In the shadow of death ♪
♪ I will fear no evil" ♪
♪ Now, I can imagine I hear
another Battle-scarred soldier... ♪
Get in the car!
Easy. All
right, I'm going.
All right.
Come on.
Stay still.
Though I walk
through the valley of
the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil.
For thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me...
- Going north?
- Huh?
Where you headed?
Melvin Griggs
Technical College.
I've never heard of that one.
Come on.
There you go. Come on.
This thing always
give me trouble.
Oh, yeah, there we go.
Yeah.
What's your name, man?
Elwood Curtis, sir.
Sir?
I like that.
You like my wheels?
Just got 'em.
Headed up to New York
to see my old lady.
You ain't but what?
Fifteen, by the look of you.
Already a college boy?
Almost 17, sir.
Still and all young.
Making our race proud, boy.
When I was your age, I was
working at a catfish factory.
Hey, kids,
turn in your straight
A report cards
for a free admission to Funtown
this holiday season.
Hooray!
Take a ride
on the Ferris wheel,
- the Tilt-A-Whirl...
- Goddamn. What's this?
Don't look back.
- Be cool.
- Try your putting
- skills against dad...
- Huh?
...at Goofy Golf.
Why?
You don't know me, do you?
No.
I mean, we just met.
I'll tell 'em that.
Keep your eyes down.
Okay. Okay.
Don't look back.
What do you mean?
Let me deal with this.
Okay.
Well, lookie here.
First thing I thought
when they said to
keep an eye out
for an emerald-turquoise
Impala...
...only a spook...
...would steal that.
The boy was walking.
He was walking.
The man just pulled up
and offered him a ride.
He just... He just...
He just got in the wrong car.
There has to be
something we can do.
Why? Why?
Why would a boy his age
heading to college...
So that's it?
That's it?
Act out of your station...
and you will pay.
White woman...
accused my daddy...
on his way home...
...from his second job...
My big,
cheerful daddy.
I saw you.
I waved at you...
from across the street
on my way home from school.
White woman say...
"He didn't get out of my way."
Two days later, still
waiting on the judge,
hanged in his cell.
God was the judge that day.
Lord, I didn't take no
more than my portion.
White man teach ya
not to take no more
crumbs than he give you.
Nope. I paid.
My daddy paid.
My Monty paid,
protecting others from paying.
Percy paid when he got home.
The Army don't protect
you here, honey.
Why?
Because your portion...
is pain.
But not my Elwood.
Not my Elwood.
Nana.
I'll be back soon.
Yeah?
You see what
Mr. Hill brought you?
Ain't that nice?
Come on, sit down with Nana.
Have some cake.
This a repeat
for you, young man?
No, sir.
You two are sitting
next to a bona fide car thief.
♪ Long gone... ♪
♪ Ain't he lucky ♪
♪ To Kentucky ♪
♪ Long gone... ♪
♪ What I mean... ♪
♪ Long gone Sam On
the Bowlin' Green ♪
Shut up, you hear me? Shut up!
♪ Long gone... ♪
You hear what I
said? I said shut up!
♪ Ain't he lucky? ♪
Shut up, will ya?
♪ Long gone... ♪
♪ To Kentucky ♪
♪ Long gone ♪
Look alive back there.
Here we are.
Welcome to Nickel Academy, boys.
Old Nickel.
All right.
You two, let's go.
You stay there.
Now, let's go.
- Good day, Dan.
- Hey, John.
Always good to see ya.
- I got two for ya.
- Rust never sleeps.
- Hey, how's it going?
- Swell.
Fine, if you don't
mind sharing a seat next to...
All right.
Let's go.
When Trevor
Nickel passed the baton
to the current director, Hardee,
he devised these four
ranks of behavior here.
You start out as Grub,
work your way up to
Explorer, then Pioneer,
and finally Ace.
Uh, earn merits by acting right,
and you work your way
on up this ladder.
Achieve the highest rank, Ace,
you graduate,
and get to go home
to your families.
If they'll have you.
That's between y'all.
Now, an Ace listens
to the house men
and his house father.
And does his work
without shirking
or malingering.
And he applies himself
to his studies.
An Ace does not roughhouse.
He does not cuss,
he does not blaspheme
or carry on.
He works to reform himself
from sunrise to sunset.
It's up to you how much
time you spend here with us.
We don't...
We don't mess
around with idiots.
You mess up,
and we have a place for you.
And you will not like it.
I'm gonna see to
that personally.
That's you over there.
Desmond, show him the ropes.
Yes, sir, Mr. Blakeley.
You know when to
say, "Yes, sir,"
which is always.
- Chickie.
- You'll be okay.
Chickie Pete.
Don't think I won't
be watching you.
Well, so...
Brian has $1.50 already.
On Tuesday, he
made, uh, 50 cents.
And finally, on Wednesday,
he made a dollar.
How much does he have so far?
He broke!
Zero, ten.
You carry the one.
You carry the one, see?
Okay, here
you go. Here you go.
Oh, my God.
- Nice.
- Jaime!
We get
to play football.
No.
- Jaime!
- They do.
Jaime!
Lookin' good, ladies.
Is that kid in trouble?
He's half Mexican.
They don't know what side
of Nickel to put him on.
What's that?
What is that?
Ice cream!
Ice cream.
You get two minutes.
You won't want more.
Hey, give him back his soap.
Hey, knock it off now!
All right,
that's enough now.
I said that's enough.
Yo, move, move.
Knock it off!
Big kids aren't allowed to
sit at the little kids table.
You eat that oatmeal
like your mama made it.
What?
I ain't never seen someone
eat this food like that.
Like they liked it.
Dumped a lot
of cinnamon in it.
I'm Turner.
I'm Elwood.
From Tallahassee.
Frenchtown.
I don't know
why you bein' so loud.
You know they got their
eye on you this week.
I'm from Houston myself.
That's a real city right there.
None of this country shit
y'all got going on up here.
Hey, thanks for that.
I didn't do shit.
You eat that oatmeal
like your mama made it.
What?
I ain't never seen
someone eat this food like that.
Like they liked it.
Dumped a lot of cinnamon in it.
I'm Turner.
I'm Elwood.
From Tallahassee.
Frenchtown.
I don't
know why you so loud.
You know they got their
eye on you this week.
I'm from Houston myself.
That's a real city.
None of this country shit
y'all got going on up here.
Thanks for that.
I didn't do shit.
That
don't bode well.
I can't help it we don't got
every can of beans he asks for.
Uh, fiver?
Uh, ten. For stress.
I got my draft
notice this morning.
You're lucky to be in Nickel.
Gonna miss your girl?
We got molasses back there?
Barbeque joint's next.
- Boss.
- Hey, don't bruise 'em.
Boss!
Hey, El.
Start with the
ones at the bottom.
Fill the baskets up by the trees
and bring it to the truck.
That's it.
Okay.
You work
this side of the row.
What're
you gonna do, hmm?
Hey! Leave him alone!
Oh, shit.
Fight!
Damn, Mike, why'd you
have to hit him so hard?
Hey!
Back up.
Ain't you the new boy?
He started it.
I don't care who was at fault,
who started it, or why.
Mr. Spencer's gonna
deal with this.
Shit.
Dead man walking.
Man, he don't even know.
He gon' learn today.
Come on, boy.
Get up.
Let's go.
Sir?
All right.
Here we go.
Come on.
All right. Let's get up.
You know the drill.
Thought you'd had
enough after the last time.
Pissed himself, again.
I'mma
hold on... and...
Be... Be still.
I'm gonna...
hold on and...
Shut up, punk.
All right,
Corey, come on.
Let's go.
Elwood Curtis.
Grab on to the rail
and don't let go.
Don't make a sound.
Or you'll get more.
Elwood, honey, blink.
"Who
shall separate us
from the love of Christ?"
"Shall tribulation,
or distress..."
"...or persecution..."
"As it is written, for thy sake
we are killed all the day long.
We are accounted as
sheep for the slaughter."
"Nay, in
all these things
we are more than conquerors
through Him that loved us."
"For...
I am persuaded
that neither death, nor life,
nor angels, nor principalities,
nor powers,
nor things present,
nor things to come,
nor height, nor..."
Young man.
Young man, do you know, uh, a
student named Elwood Curtis?
Yes'm, I do.
Thank God.
They told me that he
can't have visitors.
I just...
Would you please?
Yes, ma'am.
I came all this way.
It's a crime that they
won't let me see him.
It's a crime.
What kind of
place is this that I...
They won't let me see him.
- I'm sorry, ma'am.
- Ah.
Anyway...
I thank you.
What is your name?
It's... It's Turner, ma'am.
Oh.
Turner.
Well, I'm glad I can rely on
somebody around here, Turner.
When was the last time you
had family to come visit you?
Uh... Um...
Well...
- You know, they don't...
- You know...
I came all this way...
And
I can't hug Elwood.
So I guess you'll have to do.
Hmm?
What are they feedin' y'all?
You can't muster up a
bigger hug than that? You...
I'mma remember that next time.
Turner.
Hug me again.
What are they feedin' y'all?
You can't muster a
bigger hug than that?
I'm gonna expect it
next time, Turner.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll see Elwood gets this.
Thank you, son.
How you
makin' out here, hero?
How you like that witch doctor?
Come in here with your
damn head cut off,
and he give you a aspirin.
Come in here, head
cut off, both arms,
both legs cut off...
...and that damn witch
doctor'll be like,
"You want one tablet or two?"
How'd you get in here?
I ate some soap powder.
I have a stomach ache
for a whole day off.
Or two.
I know how to sell it.
Man, aren't you worried
they'll know you're faking it?
Man, I ain't faking.
That soap powder's awful.
But that's me choosing.
Not anyone else.
Go look.
See who it is.
Ask what's wrong with him.
Man, I'm not
asking nobody shit.
Scared?
Damn, you don't know.
Pop back there for a
look, maybe you have to
trade places with him.
- Like in a ghost story.
- Mmm-hmm.
Where's Doctor
Cooke? I need to talk to him.
I think he's
on a cigarette break.
all right.
Tell him I'm looking for
him. I'll be back later.
I've never been sent
to the White House before.
I got smacked across the
face for smoking once.
Do they do it
like this to everyone?
Man, you
already got off lucky.
Lucky?
Sometimes they
throw you in hell.
Sweat box up in the eaves
under that tar roof?
Sweat your soul outta you.
Sometimes,
they take you, we never
see your ass again.
What?
Parents ask the
school what happened,
and they just say you ran away.
I'll show you sometime.
Show you something
that's not in the books.
Where it is.
Boot Hill.
See, the problem is, Elwood,
you didn't know how it works.
You wanted to do some
Lone Ranger shit.
Run up and save a boy.
And they punked out
Corey a long time ago.
Mike and them play rough.
That's just how they do.
I used to think out there
was out there, and
once you're in here,
you're in here.
But now that I've been out,
and I've been brought back,
I know.
Out there, in here,
it's the same.
Just in here, nobody
has to act fake anymore.
If everybody looks
the other way,
then everybody's in on it.
If I look the other way, I'm
as implicated as the rest.
It's not how it's
supposed to be.
Don't nobody
care about "supposed to."
The fix has always been in.
Game's rigged.
That's what I'm telling you.
It's not like the old days.
We can stand up for ourselves.
Man, that shit barely
works out there.
What you think it's gonna
do in here?
You say that
'cause you got no one out
there sticking up for you.
I got my grandmother.
I got a lawyer.
Yeah.
When's the last time
you heard from them?
You gotta watch how people act.
What they do.
And then try to figure out
how to get around them,
like an obstacle course.
I mean, if you wanna
walk outta here.
Graduate.
Walk outta here.
'Cause ain't nobody
gonna get you out.
Not your grandma.
Not your lawyer.
Just you.
Give me $40... $40...
That'll pay you.
Do it again. Do it again.
Watch. Check it out. Check
it out. See the ball.
What're you
gonna play then?
The ball, the ball,
the ball. Find her, which one?
Give me $40.
Hey! Okay. Okay.
See. Forty.
Oh.
An Ace.
He listens to his house
men and his house father.
He does his work without
shirking or malingering.
And he applies himself
to his studies.
He does not roughhouse.
He does not cuss,
he does not blaspheme, carry on.
Why're you doing that?
He works from sunrise
to sunset to reform himself.
Now, when Trevor
Nickel passed the baton
to our current director, Hardee,
he devised these four
levels of behavior here.
You start out here as a Grub.
You work your way
up to Explorer,
then Pioneer...
...and finally, Ace.
Earn merit by good behavior,
you work your way
up that ladder.
You achieve this
highest rank of Ace,
then you graduate.
And you get to go
home to your families.
If they'll have you.
But that's between y'all.
I'm not scared of you.
My Aunt Mavis made
sure I had nice clothes
for school and three meals.
A guy at the Houston
airport started seeing her.
He taught me how to box.
The day I put myself between
Aunt Mavis and his fist,
he took me out for ice cream.
"Bring this boy the
biggest sundae you've got."
Every bite was like
another sock in the mouth.
Hmm.
Guess I wouldn't want
them to visit either.
I don't know how I'd feel if
my parents turned up here.
Hey!
Hey, look out!
Jackasses!
They know I hate that
shit. Fuck y'all!
Turner.
You know you miss
it.
Hey, Turner!
Gotta keep 'em on
their toes.
I don't
wanna hear nothing
'bout your skin itching,
you're blistered
up, it's too hot.
Y'all need to get
your counts up,
- else they're gonna say...
- Blakeley.
...I ain't
working y'all hard enough.
Mr. Blakeley.
Mr. Blakeley, sir,
Elwood's been reassigned.
Reassigned? According to who?
Oh, Ha... Harper.
Mr. Harper, sir.
You know, we need a
extra set of hands.
Well, we need extra
hands too, son.
So, can we take him?
You keep your nose clean.
Yes, sir.
Well, we down a hand.
But, boys, that
can't stop nothin'.
Turner here says
you're not a math dummy,
and you know how to
keep your mouth shut.
What are we doin'?
Sometimes
the State gives us
more than we strictly need.
So we pass it on.
For a small fee.
Community service.
Used to be a lot
worse in the old days
from what my aunt says,
but inspectors kept
sniffin' around.
Now, we only lay off
the south campus stuff.
You mean the
Negro students' stuff.
We had this good
old boy, used to run Nickel,
Roberts.
He would've sold the air
you breathe if he could've.
That was a real crook.
Had to
end up somewhere.
Beats workin'
the fields, if you ask me.
Uh-huh.
Beats getting
mangled in a machine.
Bad penny?
You keep your nose clean.
I can smell it on
him in the morning. Whew.
Keep your nose clean.
Keep your nose
clean.
Borracho.
Enough
reasons to drink here.
You think he went here?
Huh?
They say his name's
in the sweat box.
Well, this is so exciting.
Thank
you, Mrs. Hardee.
You boys are so nice
to come help out
today.
Oh, uh, almost forgot,
I have a box of books to
donate to the Nickel library.
Yeah, we
can help with that.
The box is in the
garage.
It's Trollope, and
Austen, and Dickens,
and people with names
like that.
Well, ta-ta.
Used to be worse around here.
Used to be, when you graduate,
you didn't go back
to your family.
You just had parole.
And they sold your monkey-ass
to people in the town.
Had to
work off your debt.
Debt from what?
Never thought
about it that way.
This can be a three-day
job we play it right.
We till the garden
and fix up her house.
Shit, she may even
adopt our Black asses.
Well, not you. You got family.
I'd "Yes'm" her for a
chance out of Nickel.
That ain't no freedom.
I mean, you know Director
Hardee and his wife
ain't supposed to use
us like we're slaves.
Man, all those guys
on the school board
have us do chores.
Sometimes it's favors,
sometimes it's for real money.
And it's
against the law.
Man.
The law is one thing.
You can march and
wave signs around
and change a law if you
convince enough white people.
I saw those
college kids in Tampa
with their nice shirts and ties
sitting at the Woolworths.
I had to work,
but they were out
there protesting.
And it happened.
They opened that counter, but,
I mean, I didn't have the
money to eat there either way.
Gotta change the economics
to all this, too.
Hmm.
My grandmother got
me that lawyer, man.
Make a move there first.
The courts play both
the white and the Black.
They just move us around
when they're ready.
Mmm.
Then we have to be like knights.
Checkmate.
How many people you
know done that, El?
There are four
ways out of Nickel.
Serve your time or age out.
Court might intervene, if
you believe in miracles.
You could die.
They could kill you.
You could run.
Only four ways out of Nickel.
Hour late.
I sat down to dinner
at that guard's house once.
Roast beef.
His wife made an
angel food cake.
I was in the Scouts
with his sons.
He taught us how to make a fire.
Take it serious...
What's it about?
A British
mother is trying
to marry off her oldest daughter
so they can keep their
estate and title.
Nobody wants to marry her?
She ugly?
She's described
as having a handsome face.
Damn.
I know my mother loved me.
She just loved liquor more.
♪ If you love me or not ♪
♪ I want you to know ♪
You can use the
steps right here,
if you can't swim
like your friend.
♪ Things are gonna get hot ♪
Take off your dungarees.
♪ I wish you'd stick around ♪
♪ Stick around ♪
♪ Who's to say I
hope that you will ♪
♪ And if there comes a day
When you've had your fill ♪
♪ Now just go and wait
Remembering still ♪
♪ I wish you'd stick around ♪
♪ Stick around ♪
♪ I found a girl once
Who said she'd be mine ♪
♪ Fun every night And
my life was divine ♪
♪ Till some guy came by
Who had more than me ♪
♪ So she changed her
mind And I had to be... ♪
Corey.
Desmond.
Chickie Pete.
There you go.
Elwood.
I ain't seen you lately, Elwood.
You been keeping
your nose clean?
Yes, sir, Mr. Blakeley.
You know, you may have...
grand dreams and great
designs for yourself.
But if God says
that you're supposed
to be sweeping streets,
you sweep streets,
like Michelangelo
painted the chapel.
That's Dr. Martin
Luther King, boy.
Yeah.
Grandma okay?
She says she visited,
but they wouldn't
let her see me.
"He's sick and can't
have no visitors."
"What's wrong with him?"
"How the hell should
I know, lady?"
How can they do that?
Sick?
I'm sick?
Scientist, engineer,
astronaut, the world.
All followed the
progress of Apollo 8.
For this was preparation.
An advance scout
marking the way for
those who would follow.
Those who would orbit.
Those who would land, navigate,
track, observe,
record, describe.
Bones would break
before they come loose.
They've grown
into the heart of the wood.
No
matter who you are
or where you wanna go...
...the all-new 1976
hatchback models
provide the ultimate in style
comfort, and practicality.
And for a limited time,
at all New York dealerships,
get cash rebates up to $500.
Now, award-winning
models of sedans what...
Hey.
You hear me outside?
What?
A rat run across my
feet, and I screamed.
- That was me.
- Oh!
Denise Hather,
afraid of a little old rodent?
Hush. It was big as a dog.
Hmm.
- Barked like one too.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Maybe it was a dog.
Look here.
Found one.
- This is it?
- Yeah, that's it.
'67 Econoline.
Needs a new finish,
but the guys on
125th owe me one.
I can supplement
the Horizon jobs
- with my own work.
- Yes.
Weekends,
bring Larry on. Come on.
You think you can
count on Larry?
Larry, bellyaching
about this child support
is about as dependable
as US steel.
If there's one thing
he'll do, it's work.
Well, that's great, El.
It's happening.
What'll you name it?
Don't know.
Something easy to find
in the Yellow Pages.
Yes.
- That has rum in it.
- Ooh, bless.
I got us some sandwiches too.
Mmm.
- Can you turn the TV on?
- Mmm-hmm.
Come on, let's go.
Go where?
Pineville.
Let's head to Pineville.
It's
started already.
Pineville's
south. I don't go south.
I used to know
a girl in Pineville.
If she's still there,
we get this broke.
- Now, come on.
- And then what?
"You're
married to me now."
- "And here's the ring."
- What?
Get off my back, I
ain't married to you.
Now what do I care? Come on!
You married to me,
all right, Joker.
- Now here's the ring...
- You better watch
- what you say, El.
- Hmm.
Mmm-hmm.
I'd marry me Sidney Poitier.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
I believe it.
Come to pick up the
turpentine every day.
Come out of the west,
enter the swamp,
heading across the line,
to the paintmakers
up north in Ohio.
Now we try for that train.
My mother's watch.
A deck of marked cards.
My dad's Purple Heart.
He threw it away.
Feels like I lost it though.
Uh, my big toenail.
That's all you got?
Really got nothing left to lose.
Mmm.
That makes you one
dangerous mother...
Tradition go back 40 years.
If you listen to
that birdsong...
Let's head on in here.
You gotta understand.
Sometimes, for
your greater good,
you gotta do a little
bad. That's Shakespeare.
Sometimes a bough,
it's gotta bend...
...so it don't break
off from the tree.
No.
Sometimes,
good sportsmanship,
that means letting
the other team win.
Sometimes.
I suppose that's
right, Mr. Spencer.
All right, you're...
You're not receiving me
clearly, here, Griff.
You're gonna have to take a dive
in the third round.
You mean throw the fight?
Lose, sir?
That's right. Third round.
I'm getting through to you now?
- You hear me?
- Yes. Yes, sir.
- You hear me now?
- Yes, sir, Mr. Spencer.
All right, then.
Now, you know you can beat him.
So that's just gonna
have to be enough.
Spirit of the season
of giving, Griff.
Good boy. Come on.
Good.
Well, ain't that some shit.
Don't
people bet on this?
Every year.
Man, that match ties us
to a whole 365 days
of humiliations.
♪ I am dreaming ♪
♪ Dreaming of a white ♪
♪ White Christmas, y'all ♪
♪ Just like the one that ♪
♪ I used to know ♪
♪ Honey, it's where
The treetops ♪
♪ Treetops glisten ♪
♪ Little bitty, little bitty
Little bitty children ♪
♪ They try to listen ♪
♪ To hear ♪
♪ Before the sleigh bells ♪
♪ That are ringing
In the, the snow... ♪
The first
Christmas is the hardest.
That's right!
Let's go, Griff!
Chet! Chet! Chet!
Cracker looks
like Frankenstein.
Square head.
Look at those arms, man.
Those things are pistons.
Smoked hams.
Take him to dinner
now, take him, Big Chet!
Damn.
Look at Griff's strut.
If I got
all this respect...
When's the next time fools
who hate and fear you
are gonna treat you
like Harry Belafonte.
Come on, Griff.
Right there, right there.
Turner!
Turner, that's a $100 bill!
He's putting the hurt on
that white boy, at least.
Makes me feel good.
He's dancing and ducking.
Run straight at it!
Stick! Stick!
Stick! Move him!
Whoo! Yeah! Let's go!
You got it! You got it!
Earl too, huh?
This is
it. This is it, El.
Third round.
He's about to go.
He's about to fall.
He's about to fall, El.
You don't think Griff
could knock down Big Chet
by accident, do you?
He's makin'
it look good for sure.
Jab! Jab!
Work that shoulder!
You ain't got me!
Griff! Griff! Griff!
Turner!
This isn't the fight!
The Nickel Academy Annual
Boxing Championship,
by unanimous decision...
the winner is Griff!
Let's go!
I thought
it was the second.
I thought it was
still the second.
Griff! Griff! Griff!
I thought it was
still the second, Spencer.
Spencer, wait, hey, I
thought it was the second,
I ain't know! Spencer!
Griff! Griff! Griff!
Mr. Spencer, I thought
it was the second.
I didn't know! I swear!
I... I ain't know, I
thought it was the second.
Babe, you all right?
When are you gonna give
that computer a break?
Just a
few more minutes.
They're digging, I'm digging.
Elwood!
Nana!
Elwood.
Elwood!
Can we
squeeze in with y'all?
Come on, baby.
It's been a long
wait for some good news.
Good news, good news, good news.
Well...
Lyndon Johnson's carrying on
with President Kennedy's
Civil Rights Bill.
So you know if that
Good Ole Boy's...
doing the right thing...
Things is changing.
Things gonna be way
different when you come home.
El. You can pick up
right where you left off
with no more hassle.
Hmm.
I'm sure Melvin
Griggs will have you.
And them books
you've been reading,
they ain't goin' nowhere.
Yeah.
I've been, um,
taking less hours.
Spending more time
at the church.
And I told that
trashman to be careful
with that big old truck
the way it blocks the road.
And so early in the morning,
when you can really hear
everybody get up.
Nana, what is it?
What's wrong?
You know,
Mr. Andrews...
our lawyer who was so
excited about your appeal.
I went to see him.
Went downtown, took the bus.
I paid him $200.
It wasn't enough.
But he was so adamant
and persuasive
with Mr. Marconi that he...
he and his wife kicked
in another $100.
Hmm.
The landlord was showing
his offices to a dentist.
A dentist.
When I asked for Mr. Andrews,
they just looked through me
like I wasn't there neither.
He picked up stakes,
moved to Atlanta without a word.
He took that $300.
And he knows.
Hmm.
You...
You mean he's gone.
He's gone. He... He didn't...
After all this time...
He said...
Elwood.
Look at me, son.
He said what we have here
is a classic
miscarriage of justice.
That's what he said.
And I know we hoped to
have you home by now, El,
- and I think...
- It's okay, Nana.
It's okay.
I let you down.
I'm okay, Nana.
- El, I let you down.
- No.
No, I'm okay.
I'm hanging in there.
I'm sorry, El.
I don't know why I ain't
give you that letter.
- I guess I was just...
- It's okay, Turner.
It doesn't matter now anyway.
Elwood.
Hey! Come on, man.
Yeah.
All right. Got it?
- Ooh.
- Yeah. Yup.
This might be solid brass, man.
I've got dibs on this.
Hey!
Somebody died.
What, in this bed?
Come on.
All right.
- You're through?
- Yeah.
Almost. All right.
- I'm clear.
- Clear?
Come on.
Yep.
Where... Where shall we rest?
Elwood. It's
gettin' heavy, man.
Come on, I gotta get this door.
It's weird being out here, man.
Wait till you're "out" out.
How would you do it?
Well, I wouldn't
run into the swamp.
Hide in there so
the coast is clear,
then hitch a ride
somewhere west or north.
All right, that's
how they get you.
And you can't wash no scent off.
That's only in movies.
So what would you do?
So I'd come out here
into the free world.
Snatch clothes from...
Snatch clothes from
the wash line...
...and then head south,
'cause they ain't expecting it.
Put as many miles between
me and the dogs as I can.
Tire 'em out.
See, the trick is not doing
what they know you gonna do.
Yeah, why wouldn't they think
- that you're not gonna...
- Oh!
And don't take no one with you.
A'right, not one
of those dummies.
They'll just
take you down with 'em.
- Mmm.
- Gotta go it alone.
El,
what time you think it is?
Elwood, what...
Watch out, you numbskull!
What the hell, Elwood?
You think Reverend
King's out here
in Marianna opening
supermarkets?
Here.
You dropped this.
Why you gotta carry
that around with you?
Anyone'd think you a
student.
I've been writing
everything down.
Everything what?
Our community service.
The deliveries, the payoffs,
the yardwork, the chores,
the names of everybody
and the dates.
Why would you do
a thing like that?
You told me.
No one else is gonna
get me out of here.
Just me.
Man, no... No one
ever listens to me.
All right,
why you gotta start?
Goddamn it, it's not an
obstacle course, Turner.
All right, you
can't go around it,
then you have to go through it.
And walk with your head up
no matter what
they throw at you.
All right, I get it. You mad.
And need to get it off
your chest. That's cool,
- but...
- No, I'm telling you.
There's a fifth way out.
Get rid of Nickel.
They'd put us in
the goddamn ground.
They gonna take you out
back and bury your ass.
Man, shit.
Oh, Jesus...
Man, they're gonna
take me out back too.
Elwood, I vouched for you, man.
The hell is wrong with you?
- Turner!
- Where is he going?
Turner!
Get your nig...
Get your ass back over here.
I'm tired of your shit, man.
You got the keys or not?
Goddamn baby.
It's a waste of time.
Head full of stump-water.
Give him a break.
What are you, his girlfriend?
El.
Elwood.
El?
Elwood?
Man.
Holy shit.
Long time, long time, long time.
How you been?
All right.
It's me, man. Pete Evans.
- Chickie Pete.
- Chickie Pete. Man.
- Hey. Hey.
- How you doing?
You look good.
Yes, sir.
Been ages.
Yeah.
Uh, drinks.
- Hey.
- On me.
- I got a early morning.
- No.
- So I'm gonna...
- You gotta...
You gotta let me
buy you a drink.
Excuse me. Excuse me, sir.
Can I, um...
Can I get two? Uh,
whiskey neat, please.
Thank you.
Well,
you know, I just been
saying the same thing.
I look back on it,
think back on it, and
I say that if I...
I could've played professional,
well, if things would've
turned out differently.
- You think so?
- Oh, man, I know so.
I used to...
I used to hit 'em with...
Hmm.
Oh, man, I could've
been in a funk band,
an orchestra.
I could've been like
one them cats, like, uh,
Haydn, Bach, Vivaldi.
Backin' up for Miles.
I could've been a doctor,
inventing shit, saving lives.
I got ideas, man.
Mmm.
Damn.
To Nickel.
It's a long time ago.
Yeah, my hands, man.
You know, I spent the
last 30 days dryin' up.
- Oh, well...
- Um...
My hands, man.
You know, I spent the
last 30 days dryin' up.
Oh, man. Uh...
It's okay. It's okay.
I can handle it now.
I always drank, um...
It used to be,
uh, the more I tried
to settle down,
the more I would just
get blotto every night.
You know?
I couldn't sleep in the dark.
Still can't sleep in
the dark, but, um...
I told this guy, last May...
Just tell me
how the jail...
Mmm.
The whole program...
I'm living with my sister
up in Harlem now.
You know? Until I can
figure out my next move.
I like it up there, but, uh,
you know Chickie Pete
gon' be all right, baby.
The one thing that
Nickel taught me is
how not to die.
Yeah.
How you been, man?
I've got a, um,
- moving company. You know?
- Mmm.
Trucks, employees.
All right. All
right, moving on up.
- Hey.
- I see you.
I see you.
You got a lady?
Mmm...
Nah, I mean, I did,
but it didn't work out.
Denise.
She, uh... She said I had a
lot of work to do on myself.
Yeah, I'm still
looking for the one.
I hear you.
I hear you, I
mean, it can, um...
it can be tough
trying to find someone
who can understand.
- Maybe one day.
- Yeah.
You seen any of the
other guys lately?
I ran across a few over
the last few years.
Black Mike, uh, is a
criminal.
Nate, um, strung out,
and, um, Desmond got his
arm blown off in Vietnam.
You got out in '67, right?
You don't remember?
Remember what?
You really don't remember?
I mean, I remember...
what they did to Griff.
I remember
what they did to me.
How they stuffed that one kid
inside the laundry machine.
How they made another
one eat a light bulb.
You know what I do remember?
Ghosts.
Yeah.
I remember slippin' on skin,
on flesh,
and, uh, whatever else they
had inside the showers.
Yeah.
So, um...
I don't... I don't know
what more you want
me to remember.
Nothing, man.
- Time served.
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
- They kicked me out.
- Mm.
Uh, went up to Atlanta and
then trained it up north.
Yeah.
You know, I've been
here since '68.
Twenty years.
Yeah.
- That's nice.
- Mmm-hmm.
That's real nice.
Everybody's welcome up here.
- Mmm-hmm.
- You know?
What happened to that one...
To that one kid you used
to hang with all the time?
- What kid?
- A kid.
Man, you know that, um, kid,
you all thought that
hiding spot was so secret.
- Huh.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Well, maybe it'll
come back to me.
I gotta go leak.
Hey, I gotta take off.
Oh, no, I get it, I get it.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Um...
Look, man, I, uh...
I hate to ask you, but, uh,
if you need a extra hand,
I could use the work.
Staying on a couch right now.
- Right.
- Yeah.
You got a card on you?
- Not on me.
- Well...
I can handle the work
is what I'm putting
out there, okay?
Um...
Now, you just go ahead
and give me a ring.
For the old days, I remember.
There we go.
I will.
All right, man.
All right.
Babe? Up
so early again?
- Hey.
Well, they found more graves.
Unmarked.
Oh, God...
They're asking people
to come forward.
- Give witness.
- Oh.
Is there gonna be a trial?
Mmm.
Turner.
We need more pants.
This inspection shit,
we counting on y'all.
Spit shine 'em real good.
Ain't been
eating like this
since I don't know when.
They should inspect
this place all the time.
Why're
you talking, man?
Just eat.
Not eatin', huh?
Ice cream!
Hey, y'all, you have a seat.
Son, have a seat.
I'mma get to everybody.
Hold it down.
Y'all want them to think
this some kinda circus
we runnin' over here?
Looking like y'all ain't
never had ice cream before.
Lee, put one back, boy.
Matter of fact,
put both them back.
Elwood.
What're you gonna do?
What, you think
they're gonna put your picture
on the cover of Life magazine?
You think anyone cares
what's going on at Nickel?
This is just one place.
There's Nickels all
over this country.
You're dreaming.
Mmm.
El.
What the hell?
You gonna pick that up?
Where you going?
- Oh...
- Elwood.
Don't do it, El.
No, no.
Elwood?
Hold on a minute, Elwood.
What is
it, Mr. Harper?
Need you to head
over to the farm
and find Mr. Gladwell.
Those men from the State
aren't heading there today.
They're gonna send some
other experts for that.
So, you go there,
find him, and tell
him he can relax.
I... I like
the bleacher repair.
We... We still
need to paint, too.
Can you get, like, one of
the little kids to do it?
I don't even know what
Mr. Gladwell looks like,
Mr. Harper, sir.
Sir, I would rather...
I'd rather work
on the bleachers.
You acting crazy
today, all of you.
He's got a straw hat
and a farmer's tan.
You do what I ask you to do,
and on Friday,
it's back to usual.
Elwood, wait up.
What, Turner?
That notebook you
got in your pocket,
I'll get it to 'em. I'll...
I'll do it.
Hmm.
Look at you, man. Come
on, you look sick.
I'll get it to the inspectors.
I can slip it in
their car window
when they're not looking.
They won't even see me.
In Mission Control,
they anticipated loss
of signal from Apollo 8.
With the Moon between the
spacecraft and the Earth,
all contact would be lost
until it appeared
on the other side.
Goddamn.
Okay. It's now
or never.
Timmy is scared...
...and that's natural.
But it isn't good for
him to stay scared.
Right now, Timmy's
beginning to decide
if he's gonna stay scared
of things all his life.
Now, Mission Control
and the world could only wait.
Wait for the first
contact with Apollo 8
as it emerged from
behind the moon.
See
you on the other side.
It's mighty hard
to give children the
kind of care they need.
Suppose these were
your children.
What would you do?
Oye, primo.
They're gonna take him tonight.
Tonight?
Shit.
Goddamn, I told him
this would happen.
I ain't hear nobody
out for ice cream.
When'd they take him?
They got
him right after lunch.
Where is he?
Shit.
Sweat box.
He's been
in there all day?
Elwood.
Elwood?
Oh.
They're gonna
take you out back tonight.
El.
Yeah?
- El, come on.
- Mmm.
El, let's go.
I can't. I can't.
El, come on. We gotta go.
I'm tired.
El, get up. Let's go.
El, please.
El, come on.
El.
El, let's go.
El, we gotta go.
Turner, why?
How long you been planning this?
Shit, they've
been running around
like cockroaches,
all these lowlifes.
Spencer, Hardee.
Jaime heard them talking
about taking you out back.
That was it.
Tonight or not at all.
It sounds
fucking demeaning.
There it is. I call.
They gonna shut us down?
I'll be goddamned
if Tallahassee
tells me what to do.
Will somebody
open a window?
It's hot in here.
Call.
Let's go.
Why're
you coming with me?
They'll snatch you up
in a hot minute, dumb as you are.
No outfoxing the dogs
once they on your trail.
Most you can do is get
far away as you can.
Put miles between you and them.
Tallahassee?
Yeah, good.
We gotta get far by sunup.
We can jump a train
and those dogs gonna
need wings to catch us.
They were gonna kill me
and bury me out there?
Sure as shit.
Can you ride it?
I can do it.
You got me out.
Yeah.
Whoo!
That's it, El.
You're doing great.
We got it.
Hey, Turner.
How much further?
Shit.
Come on, follow me!
Let's go, El!
Zigzag, El!
Run zigzag!
Let's go, El!
No!
He's all right!
He's fine!
He's fine, he's fine!
He's fine.
So what's new
with this year's fashion?
- How would you...
- Uh, polka dots.
Polka dots?
ACE Moving Company.
- Blam.
- Bam.
That's us.
- Yes, the big box man.
- Let's look at this...
Oh. How do we see...
- How do we see ourselves?
- How's it...
- I think we...
- Hey, what's it looking at?
- Um, two beautiful beings.
- Mm-hmm.
- Love you.
- I love you, Millie.
Turner,
what're you gonna do?
Are you really gonna go?
♪ I left
my home in Nashville ♪
♪ Look a-here what I got ♪
♪ Twenty long years
on a chain gang ♪
♪ Sweatin' and bustin' rock ♪
♪ Judge, he come from Memphis ♪
♪ Put me in the pen ♪
♪ If I ever do see
His face once more ♪
♪ He never get home again ♪
♪ That judge be long gone ♪
♪ To Kentucky ♪
♪ Long gone Don't mean maybe ♪
♪ Long gone What I mean ♪
♪ A long gone judge
On a Bowlin' Green ♪
♪ Bowlin' Green ♪
♪ Sewin' machine ♪
♪ A little kitten sittin' ♪
♪ On a sewin' machine ♪
♪ Sewin' machine ♪
♪ Sew so fast ♪
♪ Sew eleven stitches ♪
♪ In a little cat's tail ♪
♪ Bowlin' Green ♪